No hammer. No problem.
Thor: Ragnarok is a action, adventure, science
fiction film directed by Taika Waititi.
Thor is imprisoned on the other side of the universe and finds himself in a race against time to get back to Asgard to stop Ragnarok, the
destruction of his home-world and the end of Asgardian civilization, at the hands of a powerful new threat, the ruthless Hela.
Thor, played by Chris Hemsworth.
Bruce Banner / Hulk, played by Mark Ruffalo.
Loki, played by Tom Hiddleston.
Hela, played by Cate Blanchett.
Heimdall, played by Idris Elba.
Grandmaster, played by Jeff Goldblum.
Thor: Ragnarok is a 2017 American superhero film based on the Marvel Comics character Thor,
produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
It is the sequel to Thor (2011) and Thor: The Dark World (2013), and is
the 17th film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
The film was directed by Taika Waititi from a screenplay by Eric Pearson and the writing team of Craig Kyle and Christopher Yost, and stars Chris Hemsworth
as Thor alongside Tom Hiddleston, Cate Blanchett, Idris Elba, Jeff Goldblum, Tessa Thompson, Karl Urban, Mark Ruffalo, and Anthony Hopkins.
In Thor: Ragnarok, Thor must escape the alien planet Sakaar in time to save
Asgard from Hela (Blanchett) and the impending Ragnarök.
A third Thor film was confirmed in January 2014, when
Kyle and Yost began work on the screenplay.
The involvement of Hemsworth and Hiddleston was announced that October, and the
film's title was revealed to be Thor: Ragnarok later that month.
Waititi joined the film as director a year later, after Thor: The
Dark World director Alan Taylor chose not to return.
Ruffalo joined the cast reprising the role of Bruce Banner / Hulk from previous MCU films, which
allowed elements of the 2006 comic storyline "Planet Hulk" to be adapted for Ragnarok.
The rest of the cast, including Blanchett as Hela, was confirmed in May 2016, with
Pearson's involvement revealed at the start of filming that July.
Principal photography took place in Brisbane and Sydney, Australia, with the film also having
exclusive use of Village Roadshow Studios in Oxenford, concluding in October 2016.
Thor: Ragnarok premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on October 10, 2017, and
was released in the United States on November 3, as part of Phase Three of the MCU.
The film received praise for its acting and Waititi's direction, as well as the action sequences, visual effects,
musical score, and humor, with many critics considering it to be the best installment of the Thor franchise.
It grossed $855 million, becoming the highest-grossing film of the
series and the ninth-highest-grossing film of 2017.
A sequel, Thor: Love and Thunder, was released in July 2022.
The film explores themes of superhero, based on comic,
sequel, alien planet, female villain.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.